Pierre would not let this opportunity go by without trying to sell you
something.
Daniel 48 anniversary is being celebrated this coming Friday.
Pierre, whenever I make it to the White House as president, you will be my
speech writer.
Thank you very kindly.
You know, nice people, God, that's America before I start anything else.
And I really mean it when I say that.
We all came from different parts of the world, our families came from different
parts of the world.
And we assembled in peace and lovely camaraderie and so on.
We're not afraid of the police or whatever it is.
How do you defense the battery of this one?
Thank you, sir.
I just a couple of years ago, they told me I was trying to take notice.
I had no idea what that is.
So that's why I came with you because I'm coward when it comes to servers and
all that stuff.
Okay, that's just how it is.
And God bless them.
They told me, there's not a way out of me, Abby.
It's just, if some anecdote, three minutes.
He said three minutes.
I can't tell you my name.
I want to thank all the committees and everyone who is involved in this great
endeavor.
Cleveland is like great as an intervention and I love it to read the small
paragraph that I received from the president of my University of Richmond,
Virginia.
I had no idea I knew about this.
And it came to my heart.
I want to thank all the committees and everyone who is involved in this great
endeavor.
Cleveland is like great as an intervention and I love it to read the small
paragraph that I received from the president of my University of Richmond,
Virginia.
I had no idea I knew about this.
Abby, I write with immense pride to congratulate on being inducted into the
Cleveland International Hall of Fame.
I'm so pleased that this honor has been bestowed upon you and I'm grateful that
your commitment to diversity and inclusion has strengthened the multicultural
vibrancy of Cleveland.
Some nice words like that about the president of the University.
I want to thank also Mr. Mike Miller. Thank you very kindly, sir.
And I want to thank all the friends that showed up here that came.
We have relatives that came here from Virginia.
We have good friends that came here from Canton, Ohio, from Akron, from Toledo,
from all over the place.
This means this organization is so credible.
Thank you, everybody. You know what? Next year, maybe you'll hold the meeting
and join Daddy and Rocket League.
There you go.
Really, I didn't want you to bother and come here this evening, but if you didn't
show up, I would have felt bad too.
Your brother's here warms my heart. I appreciate that.
I love you.
Thank you. I was born in a little town called Pafreya, which is now famous for
the National drink, hot and wine.
It reminds me of the orders of Mary Burek.
What's the name?
Andy here for thank you, except they had the...
What do you call it?
Who would let that cook?
Okay, but now the town is very prosperous. People are very well educated.
I was there last September.
You have to watch out for the cars when you cross the road.
We were written on a street exactly, on a road, and the town is very good.
So in the 1950s, my uncle, Joe Weiner from New Pernice, Virginia, is my father's
brother,
and his daughter is here with us, and his grandson is here, and I appreciate
that coming here.
He visited us at 11, and he said, "Son, did you want to go to America as a
student?"
I said, "Give me time to think about half a second."
I said, "Of course. I'll tell you never to ask."
So I came here to New Pernice for one year, then the University of Richmond,
Virginia.
A beautiful experience happened to me at the University of Richmond. A kid, a
college kid.
Wayne Arder from Fred
from New Pernice. He said, "No, you can have it."
"No, I have it. You can have it."
I was happy that I finally accepted you.
I know he asked. He said, "You know what, Debbie? I just, I don't know how you're
going to impress me very well."
He impressed me really. He said, "We just got engaged. Next year, when we get
married, I would like for her to be my best man."
I said, "What do they do?" I said, "I don't know."
He said, "We're between now and then, everybody's fine out." That's what
happened.
We became friends and he called me after 50, 60 years or something like that
from Texas.
So this is a wonderful experience.
And to me, the fact that I studied in Islamic schools, Catholic schools,
Protestant schools, secular schools.
If you thought there are two sides to every story, there are five, six, seven
sides to every story.
But I don't respect that. Love and beauty. All we have to do in life, most of
the time, is just to listen to each other.
Don't interrupt each other all the time.
So I thought maybe, maybe, maybe, conversations on us guys, people, I mean,
people, should be like dragging on a highway.
There's a time to eat, a time to stop, a time to, you know, but no records to
drive.
Anyhow, at the University of Richmond, I really got involved in everything.
As a student of government and so on, in the newspaper, I became editor of the
literary newspaper, it's called The Messenger.
I had some proclivity, I gotta tell you this, with all the honesty, with all
the humility, to writing and this narrative and love and writing in English and
under two bread.
Except when I came back here, I lost my southern Lebanese accent, adopted a
Cleveland accent again.
I got to Cleveland. By the way, I wanted to live in Virginia.
We got married being what my wife known of, been married for 55 years, as
Pierre mentioned.
That was a miserable year for the weather. What should I do? We got married in
November.
I said, "I think we're going to Virginia." She said, "Let's try it for a year,
huh? If you don't like it, we'll go back."
And I was still trying it.
[Laughter]
So, anyhow, apply for the job, because some of you, if you read it, I work for
Blue Cross.
Apply for the job. I answered an ad in the paper. It says, "Savings and
investment."
I said, "That's a nice and clean job." I had no idea what the insurance was
talking about.
They gave a subject to memorize. Until about maybe three weeks after that, I
figured, "What? Take this insurance. I don't want insurance."
Anyhow, I set it into it, because I don't like to move around.
So, Pierre mentioned about Cameo, even American
media organization. I got involved with that. I have met one of the boys with a
lot of details.
And I love America so much. It bothered me from the college days to see
somebody who can spend years here in America,
and they have no idea what America is all about, really. I'm not as color about
American history, but I studied American history very well.
And through Cameo, I started telling the people in our readings, whatever they
go,
"If you're planning to stay in this country here, you should be a citizen."
And I teach you to become a citizen. When I teach in English and Arabic, and
when my radio program came along,
I started teaching them that on the radio. The questions and the answers, and
every time I put a bit of history in it,
so that it's so true in the hand. They appreciated that very much. That's why
the immigration people gave me a little
bit of a citation for that, and I also appreciate that. And for one thing, I
know people don't vote sometimes, because we're almost done voting, because
they don't know how.
They're afraid of that machine. We either rented, but our members rented or
bought or did something with a voting machine,
and we took it during our picnic. And I try to be, don't be afraid, I'm afraid
of it too. Nobody's going to bother you.
You put this paper right here, you wanted to talk to it, you wanted to vote to
it, to time, you pushed this button here to vote to it.
You don't make it very easy for them. And that had tremendous effect on the
people.
Again, when I had my radio show, the radio show was a learning instrument also.
I love Arabic, I love English, I love history.
I was telling them also the questions and answers, making it easy, how to
become a citizen. And many times I accompanied them to become a citizen.
I love this nation, and we have to do whatever we can to keep it number one.
[applause]
And that's why we're not too bad about it. Because there's no other nation in
the world that did to the world as much good as this country did.
And as I used to mention on the radio, what else would you rather live? Tell me.
I believe you can tell me.
I don't mean you go on vacation to this mother nation or that place. I mean to
live, where would you rather live? Right here.
And do you even know how you serve to live?
[laughter]
Good thanks to everyone. I want to also mention Father Naheu from my church. He's
a friend and a pastor. Well, thank you very much.
[applause]
And his mother also, Mrs. Samira.
You're very kind. I appreciate that. I consider you my family also. I have two
beautiful faces, beautiful people.
Thank you for coming. I appreciate that. You've been very kind. Thank you.
[applause]